<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-12-03T15:07:26-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">E-commerce Payment Processing 101: A Beginner’s Guide</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/01/e-commerce-payment-processing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="E-commerce Payment Processing 101: A Beginner’s Guide" /><published>2022-12-01T03:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-12-01T03:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/12/01/e-commerce-payment-processing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/01/e-commerce-payment-processing.html"><![CDATA[<p>Opening your ecommerce store is exciting. You’ve created and sourced your products, you’ve built an awesome website, and now it’s time for one of the most important steps — <strong>getting paid.</strong></p>

<p>Understanding how ecommerce payment processing works is a crucial part of opening an online business. But let’s be honest, if you’re not a financial wizard or very technical, you might find the whole concept of ecommerce credit card processing complex and hard to navigate. The good news is that we’re here to break it down for you.</p>

<p>In this post, you’ll learn how gateways and payment processors work together, and we’ll share some interesting info on how you can make the best choices for your business.</p>

<h3 id="online-payment-methods">Online Payment Methods</h3>

<p>Before we get into how payment processing works, let’s review some of the different payments methods customers prefer for online purchases:</p>

<ul class="checked-list">
  <li><strong>Credit Cards:</strong> One of the most popular and straightforward ways to pay both offline and online.</li>
  <li><strong>Direct Debit:</strong> Customers can enter their bank account details, making this the equivalent of paying in cash or by check.</li>
  <li><strong>Alternative Payments Methods:</strong> This includes wallets, like PayPal, Amazon Pay, Google Pay and Apple Pay, and buy-now-pay-later solutions, like Affirm, Afterpay, Klarna and Sezzle.</li>
  <li><strong>Digital Currency:</strong> A very small number of people do pay with Bitcoin or another cryptocurrency.</li>
</ul>

<p>There are a few other options you can give your customers for paying online during the checkout process, such as ACH and invoicing. However, as you can see from the chart below, credit cards, alternative payments and direct debit are the ones most people prefer.</p>

<h3 id="three-elements-of-ecommerce-payment-processing">Three Elements of Ecommerce Payment Processing</h3>

<p>Now that we know what types of payments you can choose to offer on your online store, it’s time to talk about payment processing. While there’s definitely more to it than this, an easy way to summarize the concept is to quickly define each of the elements:</p>

<ul class="checked-list">
  <li><strong>Payment gateways:</strong> act as the courier between your ecommerce website where the customer enters their payment information and your payment processor</li>
  <li><strong>Payment processors:</strong> take the information from the gateway, verify that the customer has the funds, and deposit the money in your merchant account</li>
  <li><strong>Merchant accounts:</strong> receive the funds once they are processed</li>
</ul>

<p>Sometimes people use the words gateway and processor interchangeably even though, technically, they do different things, making it extra confusing.</p>

<p>Additionally, payment service providers (PSP), also called merchant service providers (MSP), can manage the complete end-to-end process, from the technical connections to depositing funds.</p>

<h3 id="how-do-ecommerce-payment-processors-gateways-and-merchant-accounts-work-together">How Do Ecommerce Payment Processors, Gateways and Merchant Accounts Work Together?</h3>

<p>Now that we’ve explained each element, let’s review the steps for a standard transaction to see how the payment systems work together once the customer is finished adding items to their shopping cart:</p>

<ul class="checked-list">
  <li>Step 1. The customer enters their credit or debit information at checkout.</li>
  <li>Step 2. The payment gateway secures the data and sends it to the payment processor.</li>
  <li>Step 3. The payment processor checks with the credit card network to ensure that the customer has the funds to cover the purchase.</li>
  <li>Step 4. The customer’s credit card issuing bank either accepts or rejects the payment request.</li>
  <li>Step 5. The payment processor then sends the results (approved or denied) through the payment gateway, so the customer can view on the merchant’s website if the transaction was approved.</li>
  <li>Step 6. The payment processor issues the funds to either the merchant account or the merchant’s bank.</li>
</ul>

<p>What’s sometimes most surprising is that the whole process takes place in a matter of seconds — even though a lot of things are happening.</p>

<h3 id="important-things-to-consider-when-choosing-an-ecommerce-payment-processor">Important things to consider when choosing an Ecommerce Payment Processor</h3>

<p>Once you’ve collected and transferred the data, it’s time for the payment processor to actually process the payment. This is where the majority of the activities happen, from checking with the credit card company and authorizing the payment to transferring the money into your account.
Here’s some general things to know about your payment processor:</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>They should be PCI compliant.</strong>
Any company that accepts, processes, stores or transmits credit card information must be compliant with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS). This means that you and your payment processor must comply with these requirements. 
Secure Pay Service is always PCI compliant. We have a great article <em>ADD LINK HERE</em> here where we go into detail about the importance of PCI compliance.</li>
  <li><strong>They should create tokens for sensitive payment information.</strong>
We touched on this above, but it’s worth explaining how it works in more detail. Essentially, to secure your customer’s payment information — especially if you allow customers to save their payment information to use for repeat purchases or recurring billing— your payment processor should use tokenization. 
How this works is that the moment the credit or debit card information is captured, the processor converts the account numbers into a token that it can use to identify the specific customer. By doing this, you’re protecting yourself and your customers from hackers that might attempt to steal sensitive payment information.
Secure Pay Service guarantees the highest level of security for your payments.</li>
  <li><strong>The payment methods they accept.</strong>
This is probably the most important feature of your payment processor — at least to your customers. Does it allow you to accept the payment methods your customers want to use? 
For instance, while Visa and Mastercard are widely accepted all over the world, it’s a very different story for American Express and Discover. Additionally, if your store sells more expensive items, customers might prefer an option, like Klarna, to break up the payments or buy now, pay later. You want to give customers as many options as possible to ensure they complete their purchase. Secure Pay Service is proud to offer a wide array of payment options for your customers.</li>
  <li><strong>How much they charge in fees.</strong>
Now, this is probably the thing you care about most. As a small business, you don’t want to get trapped into paying astronomical fees for your payment processor, but sometimes the fees can be difficult to understand. 
Typically though, companies will charge a percentage, as well as a fixed fee per transaction. However, some may charge a monthly fee for a subscription instead of transaction fees. There are also extra fees you might be required to pay for things like chargebacks, disputes and international payments.</li>
</ol>

<div class="inner flex" style="flex-direction: column;">
    <h2 style="text-align: center">Our Pricing</h2>
    <!-- <img  src="/images/pricing_table.webp" alt=""> -->
    <table style="margin: 0 auto 2rem auto;width: 100%;max-width:540px">
        <thead>
            <tr>
                <th>Processors</th>
                <th>Retail Fee</th>
            </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
            <tr>
                <td>Square</td>
                <td>3.5% + $0.20</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Chase</td>
                <td>3% + $0.20</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Wells Fargo</td>
                <td>3.2% + $0.20</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Stripe</td>
                <td>3.5% + $0.20</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Paypal</td>
                <td>2.99% + $0.48</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td style="color:#F5841F">Secure Pay Service</td>
                <td class="circled">2.2% + $0.20</td>
            </tr>
        </tbody>
    </table>
</div>

<h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>

<p>By now, you should have a better understanding of payment gateways, payment processors, merchant accounts — and how they all work together. You are always welcoe to get in contact with us if you’d like any further questions answered.</p>

<p>Whether you’re just starting out or a fully established business, payments are a core component of your success. There’s no shortage of options for you to choose from — but you need a payment processor that addresses your specific needs as well as those of your customers. Secure Pay Service is dedicated to meeting these needs with excellence. Contact us below to request merchant services today!</p>

<p><a href="/contact" class="button next" style="cursor: pointer;">Request Merchant Services</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Opening your ecommerce store is exciting. You’ve created and sourced your products, you’ve built an awesome website, and now it’s time for one of the most important steps — getting paid.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Business Owners Need a Backup Merchant Account</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/11/01/backup-merchant-account.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Business Owners Need a Backup Merchant Account" /><published>2022-11-01T03:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-11-01T03:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/11/01/backup-merchant-account</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/11/01/backup-merchant-account.html"><![CDATA[<p>Disaster can strike when you least expect it. Every responsibile business owner knows how important it is to be prepared for the unexpected, especially when it comes to your operational systems. Is your business dependent on credit and debit card payments to survive? If you answered yes to this question, having a backup merchant account is of the utmost importance. It pays to be prepared.</p>

<h2 id="why-bother-with-a-backup-merchant-account">Why bother with a backup merchant account?</h2>

<p>Your business cannot afford the risk of losing the ability to process electronic payments for any period of time. Industries considered high-risk in terms of credit card processing are even more vulnerable. Banks can close business accounts for a variety of reasons. Many of these reasons are beyond the company’s control.</p>

<p>Imagine this scenario for a moment – ​​you’re at a travel agency and you’re planning a fantastic vacation. After spending a reasonable amount of time going through the details, it’s finally time to officially book your tour. The travel agent informs you that their credit card system is down and they can only accept payment by cash or paper check. You planned to pay by credit card. You don’t have cash on hand, which means a paper check is out of the question. This very annoying and frustrating situation. Do you completely abandon your plans and go to another travel agency?</p>

<p>This situation puts you in a vulnerable position, and that is not good for the travel agency. The chances of the client ever doing business with you again are low. Fortunately, this is a completely preventable situation.</p>

<h2 id="ensure-you-dont-lose-business">Ensure you don’t lose business</h2>

<p>The bottom line is that losing the ability to process credit and debit cards puts customers right into the hands of your competition. There is no need to take this unnecessary risk when it can be completely avoided. Secure Pay Service can have your backup merchant account up and running faster than it takes to check your bags. Why lose sales? Why lose credibility? You’ve worked hard to build a loyal customer base. Don’t let operator error or an inevitable disaster ruin your business.</p>

<p>When you have a backup merchant account, your customers won’t know there’s a business interruption. The investment pays off. Merchant account backup fees more than pay for themselves if your primary processor fails.</p>

<p>Secure Pay Service helps you protect your business for when the unthinkable happens. We specialize in providing businesses of all types - including travel agencies - with the ability to accept credit and debit card payments in person and online. Please contact Secure Pay Service today to request a merchant backup account. We look forward to seeing you and working with your company.</p>

<p><a href="/contact" class="button next" style="cursor: pointer;">Get Started</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Disaster can strike when you least expect it. Every responsibile business owner knows how important it is to be prepared for the unexpected, especially when it comes to your operational systems. Is your business dependent on credit and debit card payments to survive? If you answered yes to this question, having a backup merchant account is of the utmost importance. It pays to be prepared.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to eliminate credit card fees with the Cash Discount Program</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/10/01/cash-discount-program.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to eliminate credit card fees with the Cash Discount Program" /><published>2022-10-01T15:01:53-07:00</published><updated>2022-10-01T15:01:53-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/10/01/cash-discount-program</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/10/01/cash-discount-program.html"><![CDATA[<div class="position"><div class="embed-container"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kc0Xd0IoMI4" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div></div>

<p>It’s no secret that inflation has had a negative impact on all of us. It’s basic economics. The cost of goods 
has increased and business profits have declined. Whatever your profit margin was a couple of years ago 
has gone down. Down as your cost has increased. We want to show you how we can instantly start 
recouping some of those profits immediately. A bill was passed called the Dodd Frank Wall Street Reform 
Act, opening up a way to offset up to 100% of those processing fees you’re paying to accept your 
customers money, inflation included. The more inflation increases store prices, the more fees you pay. 
Every month, businesses are throwing away profits in the form of percentages, transaction fees, batch 
fees, and a laundry list of monthly fees, such as statement fees, PCI fees and more, just to accept credit 
cards. And don’t forget those annual fees too. Across America, businesses are taking advantage of the 
law. But many small business owners don’t even know about this option. Here’s how. Have you ever been 
to a gas station where they offer a cash price and credit price per gallon? That’s the best example of the 
business utilizing this law.</p>

<p>We as consumers are getting a discount if we pay by cash. And if we choose to use our card, we don’t 
get the cash discounted price. In essence, the gas stations are offsetting their processing fees by doing 
this. It’s called the Cash Discount program. And right now more than ever, businesses everywhere are 
taking advantage of the same law and implementing the cash discount program in order to eliminate their 
fees too. It’s so simple. There are no annual fees, no PCI fees, no junk fees, percentages, or even 
transaction fees. You simply pay one monthly fee and that’s it. If you process less than $5,000, you only 
pay $25. If you process between five and $10,000, you only pay $50 a month. And if you process any 
amount over $10,000 a month, then you only pay a flat $100. That’s it. You can literally process 50,000, 
$100,000 or more. And the highest monthly fee we charge is only $100. There are no contracts, no 
purchases are required, and no gimmicks. Just one flat monthly fee for the life of your business.</p>

<p>We are so confident you’ll never switch merchant service providers again that we are going to give you a 
free credit card terminal and we will never require you to sign any long term contracts. Join the movement 
to recoup lost profits starting today by saying goodbye to your credit card fees forever. Thanks in advance 
for your business and we promise to provide nothing less than white glove service the whole process 
through. Welcome to EasyPay and goodbye to your profit killing credit card fees.</p>

<p><a href="/contact" class="button next" style="cursor: pointer;">Get Started</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Visa &amp;amp; Mastercard Rate Hike</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/09/01/unfair-rate-hike.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Visa &amp;amp; Mastercard Rate Hike" /><published>2022-09-01T15:01:53-07:00</published><updated>2022-09-01T15:01:53-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/09/01/unfair-rate-hike</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/09/01/unfair-rate-hike.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="visa--mastercard-may-have-raised-your-fees">VISA &amp; MASTERCARD may have RAISED YOUR FEES</h2>

<p>There was a major Visa/Mastercard rate hike that affected restaurants, bars, cafes, retail, services etc. In response, a class-action suit was filed against the major card brands and settlement payouts are available to all the merchants affected…</p>

<p>Here is a rundown of the lawsiut, courtesy of <a href="https://www.natso.com/topics/guidance-on-visa-mastercard-swipe-fee-class-action-settlement">natso.com:</a></p>

<blockquote>
  <p>A Federal Court has preliminarily approved a proposed settlement of a maximum of approximately $6.24 billion and a minimum of at least $5.54 billion in a class action lawsuit, called In re Payment Card Interchange Fee and Merchant Discount Antitrust Litigation, MDL 1720 (MKB) (JO). The lawsuit is about claims that merchants paid excessive fees to accept Visa and Mastercard cards because Visa and Mastercard, individually, and together with their respective member banks, violated the antitrust laws. A number of NATSO members who may be a part of this class have sought guidance as to how this process will proceed and what steps they should take as part of this process. 
<br /> <br /></p>

  <p>Following preliminary approval, merchants will receive official notice of the settlement and will need to decide whether they want to:  (1) receive funds from the class settlement; (2) opt out of the settlement completely; or (3) object to the terms of the settlement in order to try to convince the court to reject it.  Each option has its own pros and cons, and merchants may want to consult with their own counsel before making any final decisions. Although all companies should consult counsel before proceeding, as a general matter companies that do not plan to file their own independent lawsuit going forward have decided that it makes the most sense to accept the settlement money associated with this litigation.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>If you have Accepted Visa or Mastercard since 2004, you may be getting ripped off without even knowing it.</strong></p>

<hr />

<div class="inner flex" style="flex-direction: column;">
    <h2 style="text-align: center">Our Pricing</h2>
    <!-- <img  src="/images/pricing_table.webp" alt=""> -->
    <table style="margin: 0 auto 2rem auto;width: 100%;max-width:540px">
        <thead>
            <tr>
                <th>Processors</th>
                <th>Retail Fee</th>
            </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
            <tr>
                <td>Square</td>
                <td>3.5% + $0.20</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Chase</td>
                <td>3% + $0.20</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Wells Fargo</td>
                <td>3.2% + $0.20</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Stripe</td>
                <td>3.5% + $0.20</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Paypal</td>
                <td>2.99% + $0.48</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td style="color:#F5841F">Secure Pay Service</td>
                <td class="circled">2.2% + $0.20</td>
            </tr>
        </tbody>
    </table>
</div>

<hr />

<div class="inner side-by-side">
    <div>
        <h2>What you need to know</h2>
        <ul>
            <li>Identify where the excess fees are hiding</li>
            <li>Determine the risks and pitfalls of going out to bid for your credit card processing business</li>
            <li>Recognize the proper approach to managing an efficient merchant account</li>
        </ul>
    </div>
    <div>
        <h2>A partner on your side</h2>
        <ul>
            <li>We negotiate with the processors on your behalf to reduce your&nbsp; rates and eliminate hidden fees.</li>
            <li>We regularly monitor your statements to watch for rising rates&nbsp; &nbsp; and additional fees.</li>
        </ul>
    </div>
</div>

<hr />

<h3 id="use-the-form-below-to-get-in-contact-and-well-help-you-decide-if-youre-being-scammed-or-youre-getting-a-fair-deal">use the form below to get in contact, and we’ll help you decide if you’re being scammed, or you’re getting a fair deal.</h3>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[VISA &amp; MASTERCARD may have RAISED YOUR FEES]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why is PCI compliance important?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/07/27/PCI-compliance.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why is PCI compliance important?" /><published>2022-07-27T15:01:53-07:00</published><updated>2022-07-27T15:01:53-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/07/27/PCI-compliance</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/07/27/PCI-compliance.html"><![CDATA[<p>PCI compliance is a set of security standards that are used to protect credit card information. It was created by the Payment Card Industry Security Standards Council. The standards were first introduced in 2004 and they have been updated several times since then.</p>

<p>The standards are designed to protect credit card information from being stolen by hackers. They are also designed to ensure that credit card information is not accidentally leaked by businesses.</p>

<p>The standards cover several different areas including:</p>

<ul class="checked-list">
  <li>Network security: This includes firewalls, encryption, and network segmentation.</li>
  <li>Access control: This includes password protection and multifactor authentication.</li>
  <li>Application security: This includes secure coding practices and vulnerability management.</li>
  <li>Physical security: This includes the use of locks, cameras, and alarm systems.</li>
  <li>Business continuity: This includes disaster recovery plans and backup systems.</li>
</ul>

<p>Compliance with the standards is voluntary, but it is highly recommended by the PCI Security Standards Council. It is also required by most major credit card companies.</p>

<p>If you fail to comply with the standards, you could be fined or even lose your ability to accept credit cards.</p>

<h4 id="who-is-responsible-for-pci-compliance">Who is responsible for pci compliance?</h4>

<p>Merchants and service providers that process credit card payments are required to comply with these standards.</p>

<p>Merchants and service providers that process credit card payments are not required to comply with PCI compliance if they have less than 10,000 transactions per year.</p>

<h4 id="who-enforces-pci-compliance">Who enforces pci compliance?</h4>

<p>PCI compliance was created by the Payment Card Industry Security Standards Council.</p>

<p>The council was formed in 2006 by the major credit card companies, including American Express, Discover Financial Services, JCB International, MasterCard Worldwide, and Visa Inc.</p>

<p>The council’s goal is to reduce credit card fraud by creating a set of security standards for merchants and service providers that process credit card payments.</p>

<h4 id="how-long-does-it-take-to-get-pci-compliance">How long does it take to get PCI compliance?</h4>

<p>From start to finish, the process of becoming PCI compliant typically takes between a day and two weeks. The actual time for compliance will be dependent on how long the self-assessment questionnaire takes to complete.</p>

<h4 id="how-do-you-get-a-pci-compliance-certificate">How do you get a PCI compliance certificate?</h4>

<p>Step 1: Identify all of the payment card information that is stored on your company’s computers. This includes credit card numbers, credit card security codes, and credit card expiration dates.</p>

<p>Step 2: Determine if your company’s computers are secure from hackers and other threats.</p>

<p>Step 3: If your company’s computers are not secure from hackers and other threats, make sure that they are secure before the next step is taken.</p>

<p>Step 4: Make sure that all of your employees are aware of the rules and regulations of the payment card industry.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[PCI compliance is a set of security standards that are used to protect credit card information. It was created by the Payment Card Industry Security Standards Council. The standards were first introduced in 2004 and they have been updated several times since then.]]></summary></entry></feed>